# LINUS JOHANNESSON

Tel: 070-79 79 238 | Email: linusj555@gmail.com | LinkedIn | Stockholm

# **SUMMARY**

Full-stack developer with focus on JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Vue, and Next.js for frontend, and Node.js and Express.js for backend. Familiar with databases like PostgreSQL, MySQL, and MongoDB, with experience in AWS, Docker, and Firebase for DevOps. Teaching Git at workshops.

Experienced in collaboration tools like Jira and GitHub Project Pages, as well as UI design with Figma.

# **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

# Full Stack Developer (Pro Bono) , <u>Osynlig</u> | Stockholm =





June 2024 -present

Part of a small team developing the project Föreningslivet, which aims to combat social exclusion and help people find inclusive activities through local associations. The tech stack includes React and MongoDB and it is hosted on Fly.io and Vercel." The repo is currently private and can be showcased on request.

# Teaching, Chas Academy | Stockholm

Feb 2023 -present

Giving workshops on Git, GitHub and project management-tools.

# Physiotherapist, *Medfit* | *Stockholm*

Aug 2018 - Aug 2023

Clinical work with patients. Responsible for inhouse professional training for all occupational groups at Medfits three facilities. Including planning, communication, public relations and budget.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Frontend: JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Vue, Next.JS, Redux, Axios, HTML, CSS, Sass, Bootstrap, Tailwind, Vite
- Backend: Node.JS, Express.JS
- Database: PostgreSQL, MySQL, SQLite, Prisma, MongoDB, Mongoose,
- **DevOps & Cloud:** AWS, Docker, Firebase
- Version Control & Collaboration: GIT, GitHub, GitLab, GitHub Project Page, Jira, Confluence, Slack, Notion
- Design & UI Tools: Figma
- IDEs & Tools: VS Code, NPM
- APIs & Data Fetching: REST API, GraphQL

# **EDUCATION**

Full-stack JavaScript, Chas Academy | Stockholm

June 2023 – present

# **PROJECTS**

# ShouldAlSign, personal project





September 2024 –present

Combining my current passion-project with an about me section. User agreements are hard to grasp which inspired me to develop a service that can help users understand what they sign. Frontend: Vite, React, Typescript. Backend: GraphQL, Mongoose, React, Typescript, Jsonwebtoken, Bcrypt, Express, OpenAI-API. DB: Atlas MongoDB. Hosted on AWS EC2 using Nginx as webserver. Domain from GleSys.

# Babster, Chas Academy | Stockholm



A school-project with students from programs Fullstack-Javascript, .Net, DevOps and UX/UI. We worked together to build a frontend and a backend aswell as a database on Azure. My role was mainly to build the chatcomponent and integrate OpenAIs API aswell as som promt-enginering to design what was sent to OpenAi aswell as what was returned to the chat-component. I also acted as scrum-master and was responsible for out Github-pages during the project

# **MISCELLANEOUS**